<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">🔍 Draft 🔍 - Mark&#39;s Zettlekasten</title><id>https://marklucernas.dev/draft</id><updated>2021-09-22T06:30</updated><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/draft"/><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/behavioral-leakage</id><title type="text">Behavioral Leakage</title><updated>2021-09-22T06:30</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Studies have found that introverts and extroverts can play the role of the other, but only to some extent. &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;2021-09-21T07:41&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;free-trait-theory&#34;&gt;Free-Trait-Theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; suggests that we are capable of acting out of our “fixed traits” and self-represent ourselves for the things we deem important or valuable–our &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;2021-09-22T07:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;core-personal-projects&#34;&gt;Core Personal Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;–which enhances our lives dramatically.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Behavioral leakage is a phenomenon in which our role playing, typically when an introvert acts extroverted or vice versa, abruptly break out of character showing his/her true self through unconcious body language. It is when you caught your seemingly extroverted professor suddenly look away to avoid eye contact or placed the the burden of speaking on a student when he could’ve held the floor a little longer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/behavioral-leakage"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/is-temperament-desitiny</id><title type="text">Is Temperament Desitiny?</title><updated>2021-09-08T06:24</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some studies supports the premise that introversion and extroversion are physiologically, even genetically, based. The most common ways to understand the effects of nature from nurture is to differentiate the between identical and fraternal twins. Identical twins comes from the same fertilized egg, thus share the same exact genes. While fraternal twins come from separate eggs and share only about 50% of their genes. From these studies, scientists can reasonably conclude that identical twins have more correlation than fraternal twins in terms of introversion or extroversion, even when raised in a separate household.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Though none of these studies are perfect, heritability statistic shows that &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Temperament&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;temperament&#34;&gt;temperament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; are 40 to 50% heritable. Meaning, on average, in a group of people, half of the variability is caused by genetic factors. The other 50% is from the influence of the world around us, especially our own upbringing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Low-reactive children raised by attentive parents and safe environment tend to grow up full of energy and high achievers. On the other hand, low-reactive children who grew up with parental negligence or in a bad neighbor hood, say some psychologists, tend to be bullies at school or delinquents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, high-reactive children also influenced by external stimulus but even more so than the low-reactive ones. These children absorbs more learnings from other people’s experiences. However, high-reactive temperament comes with great risk. As David Dobbs explained in his article &lt;em&gt;the Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;, “high-reactive types are more like orchids: they wilt easily, but under the right conditions can grow strong and magnificent.” These children are especially vulnerable to life challenges such as divorce, bereavement, or abuse. They are also more likely, among their peers, to suffer from social anxiety and depression. But if raised with good parenting or in a positive environment, as studies show, they tend to have less emotional problems, conscientious, and with more social skills than their low-reactive peers in the same situation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Carl Schwartz, director of the Developmental Neuroimaging and Psychopathology Research Lab, is Jerome Kagan’s colleague and protégé whose work picks up just where Kagan’s longitudinal studies of personality left off. Kagan followed his subjects from infancy to adolescence but Dr. Shwartz were curious to see what happened to them after. In summary, Dr. Schwartz studies suggest that “the footprint of high- or low-reactive temperament never disappeared in adulthood,” wrote Susan Cain&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. This implies that we can only go so far as to diverting from our innate temperament but we cannot change our temperament completely. As Cain puts it, its the “rubber band theory”, where we we have the free will to adopt different types of personality but we can only stretch ourselves so much, because a big chunk of who we are is permanent. It goes to show that the common phrase “just be yourself” has been scientifically proven to be effective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, our amygdala, part of our brains that processes emotions, play an important role in shaping our personalities. When our amygdala process fear, our frontal cortex, responsible of our decision making, tells it to calm down. Its the reason why &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Habit Loop&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;habit-loop&#34;&gt;repetition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is effective to lessen our fear. But when our frontal cortex is overwhelmed, our fear takes over. Glossophobia, or the fear of public speaking, can be overcome through sheer repetition and continuous exposure, but even with countless hours of practice, under duress, the frontal cortex will be overwhelmed by the amygdala and the underlying fear will come back to life. This shows that our fears also determine the direction our personality would lean towards. Our temperament may be the used as an indicator of what array of stimuli we might fear, and how we handle those fears, in turn, may be the indicator of what person we become.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 5: Beyond Temperament&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/is-temperament-desitiny"/></entry></feed>