<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">🧠 Index 🧠 - Mark&#39;s Zettlekasten</title><id>https://marklucernas.dev</id><updated>2021-10-11T06:43</updated><link href="https://marklucernas.dev"/><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/deliberate-practice</id><title type="text">Deliberate Practice</title><updated>2021-10-11T06:43</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;wide&#34; src=&#34;https://c.pxhere.com/images/79/9b/6de758e7c4692a0053ca0aeb1392-1637021.jpg!d&#34; title=&#34;image from PxHere (cc)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Research psychologist Anders Ericsson identified the key to exceptional achievement is through &lt;em&gt;Deliberate Practice&lt;/em&gt;. Only when you work in solitude, never in groups, can you engage Deliberate Practice, in other words, be &lt;em&gt;in the zone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Studies suggests that elite performers spend more time practicing alone than those in their peers. Chess grandmasters typically spend five thousand hours, almost five times as many as the average players, studying the game by themselves in their first ten years of learning to play. College students who studies alone learn more quickly than studying with their peers. Elite athletes and musicians who outperform their peers by a huge gap spends unusual amount of time in solitary practice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deliberate Practice requires intense concentration and deep motivation and having people around you can be distracting. Studies have found that the simple act of being interrupted is one of the biggest barriers to productivity. Also, when practicing deliberately, it is imperative that you work on something that is most challenging personally. “When you practice deliberately, you identify the tasks or knowledge that are just out of reach, strive to upgrade your performance, monitor your progress, and revise accordingly. Practice sessions that fall short of this standard are not only less useful– they’re counter productive. They reinforce existing cognitive mechanisms instead of improving them”, wrote Susan Cain on Deliberate Practice&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In business setting, evidences show that &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: When Collaboration Kills Creativity&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;when-collaboration-kills-creativity&#34;&gt;open-plan offices nullifies the efficacies of collaboration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. It reduces productivity and makes people sick, literally. Another study found that people who take a quiet stroll through the woods learn far better than the people who walk down busy city streets. The minds who created revolutionary inventions such as Linux, Wikipedia, or Personal Computer spends more of their time not with their colleagues collaborating, but their time working alone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 3: When Collaboration Kills Creativity&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/deliberate-practice"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/thoughts-on-basal-ganglia</id><title type="text">Thoughts on Basal Ganglia</title><updated>2021-10-07T07:34</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Its amazing how our brain manages to process and store information that will be recollected at the time we need them. Additionally, “chunking” our routine activities into habits is astonishing, making way for more process intensive tasks such as having a conversation while driving, or coming up with a maneuver while guarding a basketball from an opponent&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Having very little personal knowledge about machine learning, I suppose, most of the functions of a neural network are derived from the functions of our &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;2021-10-07T07:31&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;basal-ganglia&#34;&gt;Basal Ganglia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Neural networks are fed with information trained to soon become autonomous with making particulars decision. Similarly, we train ourselves to do specific activities over and over until we become good at the activity that it even becomes second nature to us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maybe someday, when computer science and neurology are completely married, we can expand our mental capacity not by making our brains bigger, but by expanding our capacity to store habits, which would effectively enhance our memory recollection and use less energy to retrieve and store information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Power of Habit by Charles Duhigg - Chapter 1: The Habit Loop&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/thoughts-on-basal-ganglia"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/basal-ganglia</id><title type="text">Basal Ganglia</title><updated>2021-10-07T07:31</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;wide&#34; src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/85/Basal_ganglia_and_related_structures_%282%29.svg&#34; title=&#34;image from Wikimedia (cc)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our brain is one of the most fragile part of our body that constantly stores new information and keep our most precious memory since our first glance in this world. If we liken our brain to that of the structure of an onion, having layers upon layers, the outer layer of our brain, from an evolutionary standpoint, is the faculty that process new information. Deep inside the core, is the basal ganglia which was recently discovered of its actual functionality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Basal ganglia controls our automatic behavior such as walking or breathing. Repeated actions or behavior undergo the process called “chunking”, our brain’s way of learning new &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Habits&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;habits&#34;&gt;habits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. As we process new information, our brain requires more memory space to store new memory for recollection. Converting routine activity into a concrete habit is one of our brains primal ability for maximum efficiency. Executing habits require far lesser brain activity and cognitive power than processing new information for the first few times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, our basal ganglia, being the core of our brain, is the last to give up when the rest of our memory shuts down. Its the reason why some diseases prevents people to form new information longer than few seconds, as if they were stuck in a particular time forever, still retain old habits and possibly form new ones, as with the case with Eugene Pauly and Henry Molaison&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Without our basal ganglia, we would never process even the simplest of task such as recognizing facial expression for not knowing where to focus our eyes on in a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Power of Habit by Charles Duhigg - Chapter 1: The Habit Loop&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/basal-ganglia"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/when-collaboration-kills-creativity</id><title type="text">When Collaboration Kills Creativity</title><updated>2021-10-06T07:58</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;wide&#34; src=&#34;https://p0.pxfuel.com/preview/427/453/229/action-african-american-agreement-american.jpg&#34; title=&#34;image from Pxfuel (cc)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since our earliest attendance in school, we were forced to participate in groups among our peers to work towards a common goal, in fact, working in groups, under a good &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Extrovert vs Introvert Leadership&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;extrovert-vs-introvert-leadership&#34;&gt;leader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, is indeed very effective, hence the saying “teamwork makes the dream work.” The big however, is that sometimes collaboration is not as effective as we think it is, even, an impediment that kills the very purpose of working as a team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alex Osborn, a legendary advertising man in the twentieth century, an author of several books, and co-founder of the advertising agency Batten, Barton, Durstine, and Osborn (BBDO), invented the concept of brainstorming, a process in which the members of a group contribute ideas in a non-judgemental environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Osborn’s Brainstorming Rules:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don’t judge or criticize ideas.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Be freewheeling. The wilder the idea, the better.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go for quantity. The more ideas you have, the better.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Build on ideas of fellow group members.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Osborn believed passionately that groups–once freed from the shackles of social judgement–produced more and better ideas than did individuals working in solitude,” wrote Susan Cain&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Osborn’s brainstorming concept caught on quick and were adopted by company leaders with enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, Osborn’s brainstorming theory doesn’t actually work in most cases. A study conducted in 1963 by Marvin Dunnette, a psychology professor at University of Minnesota, found interesting results on his brainstorming experiment. Forty-eight research scientists and forty-eight advertising executives, male employees of Minnesota Mining and Manufacturing (also known as the inventors of the Post-it), were asked to participate in both solitary and group brainstorming sessions. Dunnette divided each set of forty-eight into twelve groups of four and were given a problem, difficulties of being born with an extra thumb, to brainstorm. In another session, each man were also given the same problem to brainstorm on his own. The results were surprising. Twenty-three of the twenty-four groups produced more ideas when they were working in solitude than collaborating. Also, the advertising executives did no better than the presumably introverted research scientists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since Dunnette’s experiment, forty years later, the same conclusion were found by similar studies: performance worsen as the group size increase, group brainstorming has a negative correlation to performance. The “evidence suggests that business people must be insane to use brainstorming groups… If you have talented and motivated people, they should be encouraged to work alone when creativity or efficiency is the highest priority,” wrote organizational psychologist Adrian Furnham.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Osborn’s Brainstorming Cons:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Social loafing&lt;/em&gt;. Some people let others do the work. Spectators.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Production blocking&lt;/em&gt;. Only one person can produce an idea at once, rendering others to sit passively, potentially killing originality, or worse, forgetting their own ideas.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Evaluation apprehension&lt;/em&gt;. The fear of looking stupid in front of one’s peers.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The one exception to this is online brainstorming,” wrote Cain, “Groups brainstorming electronically, when properly managed, not only do better than individuals, research shows; the larger the group, the better it performs.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, recent studies on open-plan offices suggests that it reduces productivity and impairs memory, it makes people sick, hostile, unmotivated, and insecure. Another recent study found that people, after a quiet stroll through the woods, learn far better than walking in a noisier environment such as busy city street. Yet another study, of 38,000 knowledge workers across different sectors, concluded that the simple act of being interrupted is one of the biggest barrier to productivity, stated Cain&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Scientists already proved we are incapable of multitasking or paying attention to more than one thing at a time. What looks like multitasking is really just switching back and forth between tasks–context switching–, which actually reduces productivity by up to 50% and can be mentally exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Words of advice from Stephen Wozniak, co-founder of Apple Computer:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-none&#34;&gt;Most inventors and engineers I&amp;#39;ve met are like me--they&amp;#39;re shy and they live in
their heads. They&amp;#39;re almost like artists. In face, the very best of them are
artists. And artists work best alone where they can control an intention&amp;#39;s
design without a lot of other people designing it for marketing or some other
committee. I don&amp;#39;t believe anything really revolutionary has been invented by
committee. If you&amp;#39;re that rare engineer who&amp;#39;s an inventor and also an artist,
I&amp;#39;m going to give you some advice that might be hard to take. That advice is:
Work alone. You&amp;#39;re going to be best able to design revolutionary products and
features if you&amp;#39;re working on your own. Not on a committee. Not on a team.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 3: When Collaboration Kills Creativity&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/when-collaboration-kills-creativity"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/is-temperament-desitiny</id><title type="text">Is Temperament Desitiny?</title><updated>2021-10-05T06:18</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some studies supports the premise that introversion and extroversion are physiologically, even genetically, based. The most common ways to understand the effects of nature from nurture is to differentiate between identical and fraternal twins. Identical twins comes from the same fertilized egg, thus share the same exact genes. While fraternal twins come from separate eggs and share only about 50% of their genes. From these studies, scientists can reasonably conclude that identical twins have more correlation than fraternal twins in terms of introversion or extroversion, even when raised in a separate household.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Though none of these studies were perfect, heritability statistic shows that &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Temperament&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;temperament&#34;&gt;temperament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; are 40 to 50% heritable. Meaning, on average, in a group of people, half of the variability is caused by genetic factors. The other 50% is from the influence of the world around us, especially our own upbringing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Low-reactive children raised by attentive parents and safe environment tend to grow up full of energy and high achievers. On the other hand, low-reactive children who grew up with parental negligence or in a bad neighbor hood, say some psychologists, tend to be bullies at school or delinquents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, high-reactive children also influenced by external stimulus but even more so than the low-reactive ones. These children absorbs more learnings from other people’s experiences. However, high-reactive temperament comes with great risk. As David Dobbs explained in his article &lt;em&gt;the Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;, “high-reactive types are more like orchids: they wilt easily, but under the right conditions can grow strong and magnificent.” These children are especially vulnerable to life challenges such as divorce, bereavement, or abuse. They are also more likely, among their peers, to suffer from social anxiety and depression. But if raised with good parenting or in a positive environment, as studies show, they tend to have less emotional problems, conscientious, and with more social skills than their low-reactive peers in the same situation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Carl Schwartz, director of the Developmental Neuroimaging and Psychopathology Research Lab, Jerome Kagan’s colleague and protégé whose work picks up just where Kagan’s longitudinal studies of personality left off. Kagan followed his subjects from infancy to adolescence but Dr. Shwartz were curious to see what happened to them after. In summary, Dr. Schwartz studies suggest that “the footprint of high- or low-reactive temperament never disappeared in adulthood,” wrote Susan Cain&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. This implies that we can only go so far as to diverting from our innate temperament but we cannot change our temperament completely. As Cain puts it, its the “rubber band theory”, where we have the free will to adopt different types of personality but we can only stretch ourselves so far, because a big chunk of who we are is permanent. It goes to show that the common phrase “just be yourself” has been scientifically proven to be effective and healthy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, our amygdala, part of our brains that processes emotions, play an important role in shaping our personalities. When our amygdala process fear, our frontal cortex, responsible of our decision making, tells it to calm down. Its the reason why &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Habit Loop&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;habit-loop&#34;&gt;repetition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is effective to lessen our fear. But when our frontal cortex is overwhelmed, our fear takes over. Glossophobia, or the fear of public speaking, can be overcome through sheer repetition and continuous exposure, but even with countless hours of practice, under duress, the frontal cortex may be overwhelmed by the amygdala and the underlying fear will come back to life. This shows that our fears also determine the direction where our personality would lean towards. Our temperament may be used as an indicator of what array of stimuli we might fear for, and how we handle those fears, in turn, may be an indicator of what person we might become.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 5: Beyond Temperament&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/is-temperament-desitiny"/></entry></feed>