<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">🧠 Index 🧠 - Mark&#39;s Zettlekasten</title><id>https://marklucernas.dev</id><updated>2021-10-06T07:58</updated><link href="https://marklucernas.dev"/><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/when-collaboration-kills-creativity</id><title type="text">When Collaboration Kills Creativity</title><updated>2021-10-06T07:58</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;wide&#34; src=&#34;https://p0.pxfuel.com/preview/427/453/229/action-african-american-agreement-american.jpg&#34; title=&#34;image from Pxfuel (cc)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since our earliest attendance in school, we were forced to participate in groups among our peers to work towards a common goal, in fact, working in groups, under a good &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Extrovert vs Introvert Leadership&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;extrovert-vs-introvert-leadership&#34;&gt;leader&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, is indeed very effective, hence the saying “teamwork makes the dream work.” The big however, is that sometimes collaboration is not as effective as we think it is, even, an impediment that kills the very purpose of working as a team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alex Osborn, a legendary advertising man in the twentieth century, an author of several books, and co-founder of the advertising agency Batten, Barton, Durstine, and Osborn (BBDO), invented the concept of brainstorming, a process in which the members of a group contribute ideas in a non-judgemental environment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Osborn’s Brainstorming Rules:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don’t judge or criticize ideas.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Be freewheeling. The wilder the idea, the better.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go for quantity. The more ideas you have, the better.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Build on ideas of fellow group members.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Osborn believed passionately that groups–once freed from the shackles of social judgement–produced more and better ideas than did individuals working in solitude,” wrote Susan Cain&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Osborn’s brainstorming concept caught on quick and were adopted by company leaders with enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, Osborn’s brainstorming theory doesn’t actually work in most cases. A study conducted in 1963 by Marvin Dunnette, a psychology professor at University of Minnesota, found interesting results on his brainstorming experiment. Forty-eight research scientists and forty-eight advertising executives, male employees of Minnesota Mining and Manufacturing (also known as the inventors of the Post-it), were asked to participate in both solitary and group brainstorming sessions. Dunnette divided each set of forty-eight into twelve groups of four and were given a problem, difficulties of being born with an extra thumb, to brainstorm. In another session, each man were also given the same problem to brainstorm on his own. The results were surprising. Twenty-three of the twenty-four groups produced more ideas when they were working in solitude than collaborating. Also, the advertising executives did no better than the presumably introverted research scientists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since Dunnette’s experiment, forty years later, the same conclusion were found by similar studies: performance worsen as the group size increase, group brainstorming has a negative correlation to performance. The “evidence suggests that business people must be insane to use brainstorming groups… If you have talented and motivated people, they should be encouraged to work alone when creativity or efficiency is the highest priority,” wrote organizational psychologist Adrian Furnham.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Osborn’s Brainstorming Cons:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Social loafing&lt;/em&gt;. Some people let others do the work. Spectators.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Production blocking&lt;/em&gt;. Only one person can produce an idea at once, rendering others to sit passively, potentially killing originality, or worse, forgetting their own ideas.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Evaluation apprehension&lt;/em&gt;. The fear of looking stupid in front of one’s peers.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The one exception to this is online brainstorming,” wrote Cain, “Groups brainstorming electronically, when properly managed, not only do better than individuals, research shows; the larger the group, the better it performs.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, recent studies on open-plan offices suggests that it reduces productivity and impairs memory, it makes people sick, hostile, unmotivated, and insecure. Another recent study found that people, after a quiet stroll through the woods, learn far better than walking in a noisier environment such as busy city street. Yet another study, of 38,000 knowledge workers across different sectors, concluded that the simple act of being interrupted is one of the biggest barrier to productivity, stated Cain&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Scientists already proved we are incapable of multitasking or paying attention to more than one thing at a time. What looks like multitasking is really just switching back and forth between tasks–context switching–, which actually reduces productivity by up to 50% and mentally exhausting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Words of advice from Stephen Wozniak, co-founder of Apple Computer:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-none&#34;&gt;Most inventors and engineers I&amp;#39;ve met are like me--they&amp;#39;re shy and they live in
their heads. They&amp;#39;re almost like artists. In face, the very best of them are
artists. And artists work best alone where they can control an intention&amp;#39;s
design without a lot of other people designing it for marketing or some other
committee. I don&amp;#39;t believe anything really revolutionary has been invented by
committee. If you&amp;#39;re that rare engineer who&amp;#39;s an inventor and also an artist,
I&amp;#39;m going to give you some advice that might be hard to take. That advice is:
Work alone. You&amp;#39;re going to be best able to design revolutionary products and
features if you&amp;#39;re working on your own. Not on a committee. Not on a team.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 3: When Collaboration Kills Creativity&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/when-collaboration-kills-creativity"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/is-temperament-desitiny</id><title type="text">Is Temperament Desitiny?</title><updated>2021-10-05T06:18</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some studies supports the premise that introversion and extroversion are physiologically, even genetically, based. The most common ways to understand the effects of nature from nurture is to differentiate between identical and fraternal twins. Identical twins comes from the same fertilized egg, thus share the same exact genes. While fraternal twins come from separate eggs and share only about 50% of their genes. From these studies, scientists can reasonably conclude that identical twins have more correlation than fraternal twins in terms of introversion or extroversion, even when raised in a separate household.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Though none of these studies were perfect, heritability statistic shows that &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Temperament&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;temperament&#34;&gt;temperament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; are 40 to 50% heritable. Meaning, on average, in a group of people, half of the variability is caused by genetic factors. The other 50% is from the influence of the world around us, especially our own upbringing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Low-reactive children raised by attentive parents and safe environment tend to grow up full of energy and high achievers. On the other hand, low-reactive children who grew up with parental negligence or in a bad neighbor hood, say some psychologists, tend to be bullies at school or delinquents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, high-reactive children also influenced by external stimulus but even more so than the low-reactive ones. These children absorbs more learnings from other people’s experiences. However, high-reactive temperament comes with great risk. As David Dobbs explained in his article &lt;em&gt;the Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;, “high-reactive types are more like orchids: they wilt easily, but under the right conditions can grow strong and magnificent.” These children are especially vulnerable to life challenges such as divorce, bereavement, or abuse. They are also more likely, among their peers, to suffer from social anxiety and depression. But if raised with good parenting or in a positive environment, as studies show, they tend to have less emotional problems, conscientious, and with more social skills than their low-reactive peers in the same situation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Carl Schwartz, director of the Developmental Neuroimaging and Psychopathology Research Lab, Jerome Kagan’s colleague and protégé whose work picks up just where Kagan’s longitudinal studies of personality left off. Kagan followed his subjects from infancy to adolescence but Dr. Shwartz were curious to see what happened to them after. In summary, Dr. Schwartz studies suggest that “the footprint of high- or low-reactive temperament never disappeared in adulthood,” wrote Susan Cain&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. This implies that we can only go so far as to diverting from our innate temperament but we cannot change our temperament completely. As Cain puts it, its the “rubber band theory”, where we have the free will to adopt different types of personality but we can only stretch ourselves so far, because a big chunk of who we are is permanent. It goes to show that the common phrase “just be yourself” has been scientifically proven to be effective and healthy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, our amygdala, part of our brains that processes emotions, play an important role in shaping our personalities. When our amygdala process fear, our frontal cortex, responsible of our decision making, tells it to calm down. Its the reason why &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Habit Loop&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;habit-loop&#34;&gt;repetition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is effective to lessen our fear. But when our frontal cortex is overwhelmed, our fear takes over. Glossophobia, or the fear of public speaking, can be overcome through sheer repetition and continuous exposure, but even with countless hours of practice, under duress, the frontal cortex may be overwhelmed by the amygdala and the underlying fear will come back to life. This shows that our fears also determine the direction where our personality would lean towards. Our temperament may be used as an indicator of what array of stimuli we might fear for, and how we handle those fears, in turn, may be an indicator of what person we might become.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 5: Beyond Temperament&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/is-temperament-desitiny"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/temperament</id><title type="text">Temperament</title><updated>2021-10-03T09:16</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“Psychologists often discuss the difference between ‘temperament’ and ‘personality.’ Temperament refers to inborn, biologically based behavioral and emotional patterns that are observable in infancy and early childhood; personality is the complex brew that emerges after cultural influence and personal experience are thrown into the mix,” wrote Susan Cain&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jerome Kagan, one of the great developmental psychologists of the twentieth century, conducted a study on five hundred four-month-old infants for Child Development at Harvard, predicting, on the strength of forty-five-minute evaluation, which babies were more likely to turn into &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: The Great Divide in Personality&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;the-great-divide-of-personality&#34;&gt;introverts or extroverts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Professor Kagan’s studies found that &lt;strong&gt;high-reactive&lt;/strong&gt; children grow up to be introverts who avoids risk and are comfortable in their own self-controlled environment, while &lt;strong&gt;low-reactive&lt;/strong&gt; children becomes extroverted adults who are risk takers and outgoing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;High- and low-reactive infants seems to be the opposite of what we expect from what an introvert and extrovert adult act like based on Kagan’s studies. High-reactive infants, who are likely to grow up as introverted, are those who react more robustly to new stimuli such as balloon popping, colorful visuals, or lively music. On the other hand, low-reactive, the upcoming extroverts, are those infants who does the opposite and remain calm and quiet to new experiences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Though we are born with prepackaged temperaments that powerfully shape our personality trait, the lingering question is, is our &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folge&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Is Temperament Desitiny?&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;is-temperament-desitiny&#34;&gt;inborn temperament a permanent curse or a blessing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; that we can never escape in our adult life? This topic is further explored in &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folge&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;2021-10-05T06:18&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;is-temperament-desitiny&#34;&gt;Is Temperament Desitiny?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 4: Is Temperament Destiny?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/temperament"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/struggles-of-the-introverts-in-an-extroverted-society</id><title type="text">Struggles of the Introverts in an Extroverted Society</title><updated>2021-09-30T09:08</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;wide&#34; src=&#34;https://c.pxhere.com/images/71/bd/be1e339675e0d58a1af8a43c9fda-1639768.jpg!d&#34; title=&#34;image from PxHere (cc)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the commercial TV ads, to our school system and to workplaces, our society have always favored forwardness, spontaneity and the hail-fellow-well-met who put themselves out in the world. While the more reserved individuals shy away of their talents and overlooked at opportunities they would’ve had had they been more “enthusiastic”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parenting in 1950s believe that children who are quiet and solitary are unacceptable and that gregariousness are ideal for both genders. The quiet kids were singled-out as problem cases in school and were shunned for their solitary and serious demeanor. The parents of these introverted children mean well and were only preparing their kids for higher education and the “real world.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For instance, in the late 1940s, Harvard’s provost Paul Buck declared that “Harvard should reject the ‘sensitive, neurotic’ type and the intellectually over-stimulated’ in favor of boys of the ’healthy extrovert kind” wrote, Susan Cain&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. 1950 Yale’s president, Alfred Whitney Griswold, stated that Yalie was not a “beetle-browed, highly specialized intellectual, but a well-rounded man.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, shy types are considered maladjusted people. The latest version of the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (DSM-IV) considers &lt;em&gt;Glossophobia&lt;/em&gt;–fear of public speaking–to be a disease if it interferes with the job performance of the sufferer. “It’s not enough to be able to sit at your computer excited about a fantastic regression analysis if you’re squeamish about presenting those results to an executive group”, said one senior manager at Eastman Kodak. Ironically, its OK to be squeamish about doing regression analysis if you are excited about giving speeches, as Cain pointed out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introverts have always been unfairly treated for their “unenthusiastic energy” or that introversion are often seen in a negative light. There is roughly an &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: The Great Divide in Personality&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;the-great-divide-of-personality&#34;&gt;equal distribution between both personality types&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folge&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Why Extroverts Are Cool and Why Introverts Are Not?&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;why-extroverts-are-cool-and-why-introverts-are-not&#34;&gt;but how come extroverts always the desirable ones?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; We can conclude from the &lt;em&gt;theory of evolution&lt;/em&gt;–the strong survive and the weak cease to exist–that &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folge&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: How Do Introverts Survive The Process of Evolution&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;how-do-introverts-survive-the-process-of-evolution&#34;&gt;introverts have their own unique capabilities that put them in unique advantage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 1: The Rise of the “Mighty Likeable Fellow”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/struggles-of-the-introverts-in-an-extroverted-society"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/extrovert-vs-introvert-leadership</id><title type="text">Extrovert vs Introvert Leadership</title><updated>2021-09-30T08:52</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;wide&#34; src=&#34;https://www.stockvault.net/data/2018/08/02/253555/preview16.jpg&#34; title=&#34;image from Stockvault (cc)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of the first things that come to mind to most of us when we think of leadership are solid people skill, gregariousness, electrifying speeches, life of the party, etc., and that quite leadership is an oxymoron. It’s only natural that we require these traits from a good leader as our society &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Struggles of the Introverts in an Extroverted Society&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;struggles-of-the-introverts-in-an-extroverted-society&#34;&gt;leans toward extroverted ideals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. We strive to be the Steve Jobs or the Martin Luther King, Jr of the world and less like Steve Wozniak or Rosa Parks, though the latter are just as exceptional, if not more, than the former.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A research from a management professor at Wharton who consulted Fortune 500 executives and military leaders, Adam Grant, dug deeper into the correlation between extroversion and leadership, and found that the existing research failed to differentiate among situations what leaders might face. Grant noticed that the studies focused more on what our perception of a good leader–rooting from our societal ideals–rather than the actual result. Grant believes that certain organization or context calls for an introverted leadership rather than an extroverted approach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;His hypothesis was that extroverted leaders are better suited to lead passive followers, and introverted leaders are more effective with proactive team. “Introverts are uniquely good at leading initiative-takers. Because of their inclination to listen to others and lack of interest in dominating social situations”, says Adam Grant, “…Having benefited from the talents of their followers, they are likely to motivate them to be even more proactive.” On the other hand, extroverts “can be so intent on putting their own stamp on events that they risk losing others’ good ideas along the way and allowing [followers] to lapse into passivity&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;”, wrote Susan Cain. However, extrovert’s natural ability to inspire are more effective on getting things done form passive followers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, Grant’s research suggest that introverted leaders are better off sticking to what they do naturally and should not be construed as anything less of a what we think a leader should be. In contrast, extroverts “may wish to adopt a more reserved, quiet style,” as Grant stated, and should learn to listen more to give the quite-oriented the chance to speak at their speed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 2: The Myth of Charismatic Leadership&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/extrovert-vs-introvert-leadership"/></entry></feed>