<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">🧠 Index 🧠 - Mark&#39;s Zettlekasten</title><id>https://marklucernas.dev</id><updated>2021-11-09T06:11</updated><link href="https://marklucernas.dev"/><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/person-situation-debate</id><title type="text">Person-Situation Debate</title><updated>2021-11-09T06:11</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;wide&#34; src=&#34;https://www.maxpixel.net/static/photo/1x/Debate-Exchange-Of-Ideas-Discussion-Entertainment-222787.jpg&#34; title=&#34;image from Max Pixel (cc)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does our &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Is Temperament Destiny?&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;is-temperament-destiny&#34;&gt;temperament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; acts as an anchor that we cannot get too far away from, even with the greatest of effort to change it will only pull us back to our base personality no matter how hard we try? Or, on the other hand, does our personality traits shift according to the situation in which we find ourselves in? Perhaps a quiet disposition around family members but a comic around the company of friends? Psychologists call this the “person-situation” debate.&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Professor Brian Little, former Harvard University psychology lecturer and winner for the 3M Teaching Fellowship, despite his brilliant and engaging lectures with a flair for entertainment that always ended with a hearty applause, he calls himself a devout introvert. Little believes that our personality shape our lives in profound ways based on psychological mechanisms that last our lifetime. This fall squarely on the “person” side of the debate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the other side of the debate, a group of psychologist known as the &lt;em&gt;Situationist&lt;/em&gt;. “Situationism posits that our generalizations about people, including the words we use to describe one another–shy, aggressive, conscientious, agreeable–are misleading. There is no core self; there are only the various selves of Situations X, Y, Z,” wrote Susan Cain.&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34; id=&#34;fnref2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt; This view of personality rose to popularity in 1968 when Walter Mischel Published &lt;em&gt;Personality and Assessment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn3&#34; id=&#34;fnref3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, rivaling the idea of the “person” side of the debate arguing that situational factors predicts behavior of people more accurately.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Decades after the debate has been raised, Situationism prevailed. “The postmodern view of self that emerged around this time, influenced by theorist like Erving Goffman, author of &lt;em&gt;The Presentation of Self in Everyday Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn4&#34; id=&#34;fnref4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, suggested that social life is a performance and social masks are our true selves,” Cain explains, “Many researchers doubted whether personality traits even existed in any meaningful sense. Personality researchers had trouble finding jobs.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, just as the &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Temperament&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;temperament&#34;&gt;nature-nurture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; debate melted down to interactionism&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn5&#34; id=&#34;fnref5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, person-situation debate has been superseded by a more nuanced understanding. Personality psychologists accepted that fluctuations in our behavior are real and situation-dependent, while making aware that there truly are fixed personality traits each of us cannot escape from.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even Mischel admitted that some traits are fixed, but believed that they tend to occur in patterns. Brian Little tend to posit the same claim as he almost created single-handedly the &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folge&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Free-Trait Theory&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;free-trait-theory&#34;&gt;Free-Trait Theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, claiming that fixed traits and free traits coexist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &#34;A man has as many social selves as there are distinct groups of persons
    about whose opinion he cares. He generally shows a different side of himself
    to each of these different groups.&#34;
    - William James
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Person%E2%80%93situation_debate&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Person%E2%80%93situation_debate&lt;/a&gt; “Person–situation debate”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 9: When Should You Act More Extroverted Than You Really Are?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn3&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walter_Mischel&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walter_Mischel&lt;/a&gt; “Walter Mischel”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref3&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn4&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Presentation_of_Self_in_Everyday_Life&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Presentation_of_Self_in_Everyday_Life&lt;/a&gt; “The Presentation of Self in Everyday Life”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref4&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn5&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interactionism&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interactionism&lt;/a&gt; “Interactionism”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref5&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/person-situation-debate"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/soft-power</id><title type="text">Soft Power</title><updated>2021-11-05T06:47</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;wide&#34; src=&#34;https://www.maxpixel.net/static/photo/1x/Mohandas-Karamchand-Gandhi-Peace-Movement-1930-67483.jpg&#34; title=&#34;image from Max Pixel (cc)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As some may notice, soft power is not an oxymoron. In Western Culture, being soft is not an attribute of a person with power, in fact, it can even be seen as a weakness and a submissive trait. However, eastern cultures, such as the Asians have just the opposite view. Preston Ni, communications professor at Foothill College, defines soft power as “quiet persistence.” As Ni puts it “Aggressive power beats you up; soft power wins you over.” Soft power is what makes people rally not by dynamism but through conviction, and can change people’s lives not by charisma but through caring.&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mahatma Ghandi, an introverted indian man who were constitutionally shy and reserved, shook the world in a gentle way and changed countless of people’s lives through passive resistance and &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Extrovert vs Introvert Leadership&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;extrovert-vs-introvert-leadership&#34;&gt;quiet leadership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Once the young Ghandi learned to manage his shyness, but never really overcame it, he traveled to England to study law against the will of the leaders of his subcaste Modhi Bania. The members of the caste where forbidden to eat meat and thought it is impossible to abstain from meat in England. But Ghandi thought otherwise since he already devoted himself to his mother to abstain from meat, and therefore got himself excommunicated, even after his return from England several years later completely abstained from consuming meat. Being excommunicated meant prohibition to eat or drink at the homes of his fellow caste members, including his own family. His sister and in-laws offered to host him at their homes surreptitiously, but he turned them all down. He abode by the rules of his caste as he did not see fit to retaliate or protest against the leaders of the caste. Eventually, through his persistence and compliance, the subcaste relented and even helped him later in his political work, without expecting anything in return. He later wrote, “It is my conviction that all these good things are due to my non-resistance. Had I agitated for being admitted to the caste, had I attempted to divide it into more camps, had I provoked the castemen, they would surely have retaliated, and instead of steering clear of the storm, I should, on arrival from England, have found myself in whirlpool of agitation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, his quiet conviction did not bode well for his law career. He struggled to wade through discrimination and disbelief in his &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Temperament&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;temperament&#34;&gt;temperament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; as a lawyer, even by his own friends and colleagues. They said he was weak and should have stood up for his belief but Ghandi saw the power “to appreciate the beauty of compromise.” His passivity, as the word &lt;em&gt;Satyagraha&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34; id=&#34;fnref2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt; implies, was not weakness at all. “It meant focusing on an ultimate goal and refusing to divert energy to unnecessary skirmishes along the way. Restraint, Ghandi believed, was one of his greatest assets”, Susan Cain wrote.&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Later in his career, he became one of the greatest political and spiritual leaders that would receive the honor as the “father of the nation” in India with his efforts to lead the non-violent independence movement against British rule and an advocate of the civil rights of Indians in South Africa.&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn3&#34; id=&#34;fnref3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Soft power is leadership &#34;by water rather than by fire.&#34; Soft power is quiet
    persistence ~ Preston Ni
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 8: Soft Power&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satyagraha&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satyagraha&lt;/a&gt; Satyagraha, meaning “holding onto truth” in Sanskrit and Hindi, a concept introduced by Mahatma Gandhi to designate a determinded but nonviolent resistance to evil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn3&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biography.com/activist/mahatma-gandhi&#34;&gt;https://www.biography.com/activist/mahatma-gandhi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref3&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/soft-power"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/are-introverts-smarter-than-extroverts</id><title type="text">Are Introverts Smarter Than Extroverts?</title><updated>2021-10-28T08:29</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;By nature, introverts are analytical and introspective people who “wait before pouncing” at every possible opportunity. On the other hand, extroverts are risk takers and &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Reward Sensitivity&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;reward-sensitivity&#34;&gt;reward-sensitive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; people who “act before thinking” to get where they want to be as quickly as possible. Of course, not everyone falls solely on either side of the spectrum. Some are partial to both categories while others lie smack dab in the middle. However, despite the &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Temperament&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;temperament&#34;&gt;temperamental&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; difference between the two &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: The Great Divide in Personality&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;the-great-divide-of-personality&#34;&gt;personality traits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, neither has superior intellect over the other.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Statistically speaking, according to IQ scores, the two types are equally intelligent. As the psychologist Gerald Matthews describes in his work, introverts think more carefully than extroverts. Extroverts approach problem-solving head-on, taking shortcuts along the way, trading accuracy for speed which makes it easier to commit mistakes, and giving up altogether when the task gets overwhelmingly frustrating. Conversely, introverts digest information thoroughly, better at &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Delayed Gratification&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;delayed-gratification&#34;&gt;delaying gratification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, takes more preparation than extroverts do which makes it easier to stick with problems longer.&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wise words from the world-renowned genius theoretical physicist, Albert Einstein: “It’s not that I’m so smart, it’s just that I stay with problems longer.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    No. Statistically, IQ scores shows that the two types are equal in
    intellect. The difference lie only on temperament.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 7: Why Did Wall Street Crash and Warren Buffet Prosper?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/are-introverts-smarter-than-extroverts"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/delayed-gratification</id><title type="text">Delayed Gratification</title><updated>2021-10-27T07:52</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Delay of Gratification is the act of resisting an immediate pleasure in hope of obtaining a more gratifying reward in the future. As simple as it sounds, as it turns out, most of us, if not all, struggles to resist our impulses to take immediately available rewards even with the knowledge that a bigger reward is available had we resisted. This applies to almost every aspect of our life: from our occupation, to our education, to our hobbies, to our life choices. The famous &lt;em&gt;Marshmallow Test&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, despite of what we think of ourselves, outlines our very weakness when it comes to immediate rewards and self discipline. It shows our ability to resist temptation which tells a lot about our &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: The Great Divide in Personality&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;the-great-divide-of-personality&#34;&gt;personality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and potentially vaguely predict our future. In our defense, self-discipline can taught to fight our most primal urges. But part of our innate &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Is Temperament Destiny?&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;is-temperament-destiny&#34;&gt;temperament stick around&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; even how much we train to resist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Marshmallow Test | Igniter Media | Church Video&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QX_oy9614HQ&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, a psychologist at the University of Wisconsin, Joseph Newman, conducted a study where participants were to play a game: simply the more points gained, the more money won. Participants were given a button and a screen that flashes twelve different numbers randomly, and were instructed that a “good” number will win them points and a “bad” number will lose them points; pressing nothing at all will do nothing. Through trial and error, participants eventually learned that the number four is a good number and nine is not. Instinctively, we know good enough not to press the button when number nine comes across the screen, except that sometimes people press the button in spite of this knowledge. Newman found that extroverts were likely to make this mistake. In the words of the psychologists John Brebner and Chris Cooper who have shown that extroverts think less and act faster on such tasks, introverts are “geared to inspect” and extroverts are “geared to respond.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the most interesting part of the experiment is not what extroverts do &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; they hit the button, but what they do &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt;. “When introverts hit the number nine button and find they’ve lost a point, they slow down before moving on to the next number, as if to reflect on what went wrong. But extroverts not only fail to slow down, &lt;em&gt;they actually speed up,&lt;/em&gt;” wrote Susan Cain.&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34; id=&#34;fnref2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Newman explains, it makes perfect sense because focusing on achieving our goals as &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Reward Sensitivity&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;reward-sensitivity&#34;&gt;reward-sensitive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; extroverts do, we don’t want anything to get in our way, we speed up to reach our goals quicker. Yet, it is crucial that we take a pause to process our misstep so we can learn from it. If extroverts were to be &lt;em&gt;forced&lt;/em&gt; to pause at such instance, Newman says, they’ll do just as well as introverts did. But left on their own devices, they don’t stop. In contrast, introverts are programmed to kill their &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Reward Sensitivity&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;reward-sensitivity&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;buzz&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and scan for problems. However, this doesn’t imply that introverts are smarter than extroverts, as explained in the &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folge&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;2021-10-28T08:29&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;are-introverts-smarter-than-extroverts&#34;&gt;Are Introverts Smarter Than Extroverts?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Delay of Gratification is the act of resisting an immediate pleasure in hope
    of obtaining a more gratifying reward in the future. Introverts are
    generally more patient because extroverts are more reward-sensitive,
    speeding things up to reach their goals quicker.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QX_oy9614HQ&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QX_oy9614HQ&lt;/a&gt; (The Marshmallow Test | Igniter Media | Church Video)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 7: Why Did Wall Street Crash and Warren Buffet Prosper?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/delayed-gratification"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/zettelkasten</id><title type="text">Zettelkasten</title><updated>2021-10-27T07:42</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;wide&#34; src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/33/Zettelkasten_%28514941699%29.jpg&#34; title=&#34;image from Wikimedia Commons (cc)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zettelkasten, a German word for “slip-box”, is a note-taking method and a personal knowledge management used in research and study&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. The notes contain &lt;em&gt;metadata&lt;/em&gt; for associating notes with each other, such as tags that describe the key aspects of the note. Also, the notes are numbered hierarchically so that new notes can be inserted in between under the appropriate number:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-none&#34;&gt;1. Topic 1
  1.a Subtopic 1
  1.b Subtopic 2
    1.b.i Inner subtopic 1
    1.b.ii Inner subtopic 2
2. Topic 2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This method eliminates the need for dynamically organizing notes with folder structures which can be time consuming and hard to make connections with. It also makes it easier to draw connections and relationships that can be useful in research and creative writing which otherwise would have been difficult with other information management system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zettelkasten has been around since the 1500s and used by individual researchers and organizations for managing information. However, it was popularized by the sociologist Niklas Luhmann&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34; id=&#34;fnref2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt; who built his own zettelkasten of some 90,000 index cards for his research which he claimed to be his secret for extraordinarily writing over 70 books and 400 scholarly articles in his lifetime. Luhmann linked the cards together by assigning each a unique index number based on a branching hierarchy. The index cards were digitized and made available online in 2019&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn3&#34; id=&#34;fnref3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zettelkasten Note-Taking Method: Simply Explained&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn4&#34; id=&#34;fnref4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rOSZOCoqOo8&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zettelkasten&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zettelkasten&lt;/a&gt; “Zettelkasten”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niklas_Luhmann&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niklas_Luhmann&lt;/a&gt; “Niklas Luhmann”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn3&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20200712193714/https://www.heise.de/newsticker/meldung/Missing-Link-Luhmanns-Denkmaschine-endlich-im-Netz-4364512.html&#34;&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20200712193714/https://www.heise.de/newsticker/meldung/Missing-Link-Luhmanns-Denkmaschine-endlich-im-Netz-4364512.html&lt;/a&gt; “Missing Link: Luhmanns Denkmaschine endlich im Netz”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref3&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn4&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rOSZOCoqOo8&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rOSZOCoqOo8&lt;/a&gt; “Zettelkasten Note-Taking Method: Simply Explained”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref4&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/zettelkasten"/></entry></feed>