<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">🧠 Index 🧠 - Mark&#39;s Zettlekasten</title><id>https://marklucernas.dev</id><updated>2021-11-16T06:14</updated><link href="https://marklucernas.dev"/><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/free-trait-theory</id><title type="text">Free Trait Theory</title><updated>2021-11-16T06:14</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;wide&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2016/10/24/23/11/doors-1767563_960_720.jpg&#34; title=&#34;image from Pixabay (cc)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Professor Brian Little, a former Harvard University Lecturer and Winner of the 3M Teaching Fellowship almost single-handedly created the Free Trait Theory believing that fixed trait and free traits coexist. Free Trait Theory suggests that we are born with innate personality traits–fixed traits–but we are able to come out of our comfort zone and play a role–free trait–in the service of &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folge&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Core Personal Projects&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;core-personal-projects&#34;&gt;core personal projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Core personal projects are the things we value the most that improve our lives significantly. However, pursuit of such projects with no deeper values motivating us to play a pseudo-personality is called &lt;em&gt;self-negation&lt;/em&gt; which can be exhausting and unhealthy&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, working towards our core personal projects requiring prolonged role playing can be cumbersome. Professor Little believes we ought to have our own “restorative niches” or a place where we can truly be ourselves as much as possible. A place we can “recharge” ourselves in: a quite place perfect for an introvert without the burden of entertaining a company, or a raving party surrounded by hundreds of extroverts. For Professor Little, it was his short trips to the restroom in-between speeches were he breaks out of character to regain energy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But, not every time we get the opportunity to have restorative niches and others who are important to us require our time and attention, matching their moods, or participating in activities they are interested in, bringing us to the final piece of the Free Trait Theory. Free Trait Agreement. An acknowledgement that we’ll each act out of character for sometime in exchange for being ourselves the rest of the time. “It’s a Free Trait Agreement when a wife who wants to go out every Saturday night”, Susan Cain wrote, “and a Husband who wants to relax by the fire work out a schedule: &lt;em&gt;half the time we’ll go out, and half the time we’ll stay home&lt;/em&gt;.” Lack of Free Trait Agreement can lead to a situation where others give certain expectation of you that you don’t do so naturally–a persona that others knew that you feel obliged to serve up to, “reputational confusion” as Professor Little calls it. Introducing yourself to a new group of friends as a party animal while you secretly retreat every chance you get back to your elements is an instance of a reputational confusion that drains energy. More often than not, toxic relationships lack Free Trait Agreement, and as much as we hate to admit, its a burrow we dug ourselves into, blaming others if we fail to meet their expectations that we placed ourselves in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 9: When Should You Act More Extroverted Than You Really Are?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/free-trait-theory"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/core-personal-projects</id><title type="text">Core Personal Projects</title><updated>2021-11-10T07:12</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Professor Brian Little, a renowned Former Harvard University Lecturer, call the things we value and love the most our core personal projects. In Little’s &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Free Trait Theory&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;free-trait-theory&#34;&gt;Free Trait Theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, it suggests that we are born with absolute cultural personality traits and were only able to act out of it if we work towards core personal projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Core personal projects, according to Little, dramatically improve our lives when we consider it meaningful, manageable, unduly stressful, and supported by others. Often times, we give great emotional weight to our core personal projects that when asked “How things are going?” we may respond with a rehearsed answer, but our true response relates to how well stand we it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Professor Little, a high &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Self-Monitoring&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;self-monitoring&#34;&gt;self-monitor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, a consummate introvert who loves his students dearly, is only able to break out of character and passionately lecture like a performer because of his core personal projects: opening students’ mind and attending to their well-being.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finding your core personal projects can be quite difficult especially for &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Struggles of the Introverts in an Extroverted Society&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;struggles-of-the-introverts-in-an-extroverted-society&#34;&gt;introverts who have been living under extroverted ideals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Susan Cain, in her book&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, offers 3 steps on finding your own core personal projects:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Think back to what you loved doing as a child. How did you answer what you want to be when you grew up? Our unadulterated childhood whims may reveal our true desire.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pay attention to the work you gravitate to. You may not like what you do with your current job, but we often do things as a means to our goal.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Finally, pay attention to what you envy. “Jealousy is an ugly emotion, but it tells the truth.” We desire the things we are envious of which may give away a hint to a suitable core personal project.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldr rounded shadow-2xl&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Our core personal projects are the things we value and love the most. It
    improve our lives significantly and give great emotional weight to it.
    Free Trait theory suggests we are only able to pretend someone we are not if
    we work towards a core personal project.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 9: When Should You Act More Extroverted Than You Really Are?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/core-personal-projects"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/self-monitoring</id><title type="text">Self-Monitoring</title><updated>2021-11-09T07:09</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Self-monitoring is what psychologists call the tendency of a pseudo-introvert or -extrovert to act out of their comfort personality. However, we can only hide behind our masks for so long that &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Free Trait Theory&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;free-trait-theory&#34;&gt;we will eventually break out of character&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, even for a moment. This phenomenon is called &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folge&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Behavioral Leakage&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;behavioral-leakage&#34;&gt;behavioral leakage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, “when our true selves seep out via unconscious body language,” as Susan Cain puts it&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Self-monitors are adept at keeping in character, modifying their behaviors to the social demands of the situation. &lt;strong&gt;High self-monitors&lt;/strong&gt; are the social butterflies that can blend in any company at a drop of a hat. In contrast, &lt;strong&gt;low self-monitors&lt;/strong&gt; base their behavior on their own internal compass, have smaller collection of social masks to play in, making them less sensitive to social cues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 9: When Should You Act More Extroverted Than You Really Are?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/self-monitoring"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/person-situation-debate</id><title type="text">Person-Situation Debate</title><updated>2021-11-09T06:11</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;wide&#34; src=&#34;https://www.maxpixel.net/static/photo/1x/Debate-Exchange-Of-Ideas-Discussion-Entertainment-222787.jpg&#34; title=&#34;image from Max Pixel (cc)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Does our &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Temperament&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;temperament&#34;&gt;temperament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; act as &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Is Temperament Destiny?&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;is-temperament-destiny&#34;&gt;an anchor that we cannot get too far away from&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, even with the greatest of effort to change it will only pull us back to our base personality no matter how hard we try? Or, on the other hand, does our personality traits shift according to the situation in which we find ourselves in? Perhaps a quiet disposition around family members but a comic around the company of friends? Psychologists call this the “person-situation” debate.&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Professor Brian Little, former Harvard University psychology lecturer and winner for the 3M Teaching Fellowship, despite his brilliant and engaging lectures with a flair for entertainment that always ended with a hearty applause, he calls himself a devout introvert. Little believes that our personality shape our lives in profound ways based on psychological mechanisms that last our lifetime. This fall squarely on the “person” side of the debate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the other side of the debate, a group of psychologist known as the &lt;em&gt;Situationist&lt;/em&gt;. “Situationism posits that our generalizations about people, including the words we use to describe one another–shy, aggressive, conscientious, agreeable–are misleading. There is no core self; there are only the various selves of Situations X, Y, Z,” wrote Susan Cain.&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34; id=&#34;fnref2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt; This view of personality rose to popularity in 1968 when Walter Mischel Published &lt;em&gt;Personality and Assessment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn3&#34; id=&#34;fnref3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, rivaling the idea of the “person” side of the debate arguing that situational factors predicts behavior of people more accurately.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Decades after the debate has been raised, Situationism prevailed. “The postmodern view of self that emerged around this time, influenced by theorist like Erving Goffman, author of &lt;em&gt;The Presentation of Self in Everyday Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn4&#34; id=&#34;fnref4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, suggested that social life is a performance and social masks are our true selves,” Cain explains, “Many researchers doubted whether personality traits even existed in any meaningful sense. Personality researchers had trouble finding jobs.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, just as the &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Temperament&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;temperament&#34;&gt;nature-nurture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; debate melted down to interactionism&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn5&#34; id=&#34;fnref5&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, person-situation debate has been superseded by a more nuanced understanding. Personality psychologists accepted that fluctuations in our behavior are real and situation-dependent, while making aware that there truly are fixed personality traits each of us cannot escape from.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even Mischel admitted that some traits are fixed, but believed that they tend to occur in patterns. Brian Little tend to posit the same claim as he almost created single-handedly the &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folge&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Free Trait Theory&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;free-trait-theory&#34;&gt;Free Trait Theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, claiming that fixed traits and free traits coexist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldr rounded shadow-2xl&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &#34;A man has as many social selves as there are distinct groups of persons
    about whose opinion he cares. He generally shows a different side of himself
    to each of these different groups.&#34;
    - William James
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Person%E2%80%93situation_debate&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Person%E2%80%93situation_debate&lt;/a&gt; “Person–situation debate”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 9: When Should You Act More Extroverted Than You Really Are?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn3&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walter_Mischel&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walter_Mischel&lt;/a&gt; “Walter Mischel”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref3&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn4&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Presentation_of_Self_in_Everyday_Life&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Presentation_of_Self_in_Everyday_Life&lt;/a&gt; “The Presentation of Self in Everyday Life”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref4&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn5&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interactionism&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interactionism&lt;/a&gt; “Interactionism”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref5&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/person-situation-debate"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/soft-power</id><title type="text">Soft Power</title><updated>2021-11-05T06:47</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;wide&#34; src=&#34;https://www.maxpixel.net/static/photo/1x/Mohandas-Karamchand-Gandhi-Peace-Movement-1930-67483.jpg&#34; title=&#34;image from Max Pixel (cc)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As some may notice, soft power is not an oxymoron. In Western Culture, being soft is not an attribute of a person with power, in fact, it can even be seen as a weakness and a submissive trait. However, eastern cultures, such as the Asians have just the opposite view. Preston Ni, communications professor at Foothill College, defines soft power as “quiet persistence.” As Ni puts it “Aggressive power beats you up; soft power wins you over.” Soft power is what makes people rally not by dynamism but through conviction, and can change people’s lives not by charisma but through caring.&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mahatma Ghandi, an introverted indian man who were constitutionally shy and reserved, shook the world in a gentle way and changed countless of people’s lives through passive resistance and &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Extrovert vs Introvert Leadership&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;extrovert-vs-introvert-leadership&#34;&gt;quiet leadership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Once the young Ghandi learned to manage his shyness, but never really overcame it, he traveled to England to study law against the will of the leaders of his subcaste Modhi Bania. The members of the caste where forbidden to eat meat and thought it is impossible to abstain from meat in England. But Ghandi thought otherwise since he already devoted himself to his mother to abstain from meat, and therefore got himself excommunicated, even after his return from England several years later completely abstained from consuming meat. Being excommunicated meant prohibition to eat or drink at the homes of his fellow caste members, including his own family. His sister and in-laws offered to host him at their homes surreptitiously, but he turned them all down. He abode by the rules of his caste as he did not see fit to retaliate or protest against the leaders of the caste. Eventually, through his persistence and compliance, the subcaste relented and even helped him later in his political work, without expecting anything in return. He later wrote, “It is my conviction that all these good things are due to my non-resistance. Had I agitated for being admitted to the caste, had I attempted to divide it into more camps, had I provoked the castemen, they would surely have retaliated, and instead of steering clear of the storm, I should, on arrival from England, have found myself in whirlpool of agitation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, his quiet conviction did not bode well for his law career. He struggled to wade through discrimination and disbelief in his &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Temperament&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;temperament&#34;&gt;temperament&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; as a lawyer, even by his own friends and colleagues. They said he was weak and should have stood up for his belief but Ghandi saw the power “to appreciate the beauty of compromise.” His passivity, as the word &lt;em&gt;Satyagraha&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn2&#34; id=&#34;fnref2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt; implies, was not weakness at all. “It meant focusing on an ultimate goal and refusing to divert energy to unnecessary skirmishes along the way. Restraint, Ghandi believed, was one of his greatest assets”, Susan Cain wrote.&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Later in his career, he became one of the greatest political and spiritual leaders that would receive the honor as the “father of the nation” in India with his efforts to lead the non-violent independence movement against British rule and an advocate of the civil rights of Indians in South Africa.&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn3&#34; id=&#34;fnref3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldr rounded shadow-2xl&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Soft power is leadership &#34;by water rather than by fire.&#34; Soft power is quiet
    persistence ~ Preston Ni
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 8: Soft Power&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn2&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satyagraha&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satyagraha&lt;/a&gt; Satyagraha, meaning “holding onto truth” in Sanskrit and Hindi, a concept introduced by Mahatma Gandhi to designate a determinded but nonviolent resistance to evil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn3&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.biography.com/activist/mahatma-gandhi&#34;&gt;https://www.biography.com/activist/mahatma-gandhi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref3&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/soft-power"/></entry></feed>