<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title type="text">🧠 Index 🧠 - Mark&#39;s Zettlekasten</title><id>https://marklucernas.dev</id><updated>2021-10-22T07:08</updated><link href="https://marklucernas.dev"/><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/reward-sensitivity</id><title type="text">Reward Sensitivity</title><updated>2021-10-22T07:08</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;wide&#34; src=&#34;https://www.thebluediamondgallery.com/wooden-tile/images/reward.jpg&#34; title=&#34;image from The Blue Diamond Gallery (cc)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In an attempt to simplify reward sensitivity, it is the measure of our motivation to seek reward such as money, sex, or fame and influence. A highly reward-sensitive person can get so excited by the prospect of the reward that it impairs good judgement and ignore obvious warning signals. While a reward-insensitive person can get too careful that they miss out on opportunities they should have taken. It is the &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Trade-Off Theory&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;trade-off-theory&#34;&gt;trade-off&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; that separates the &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: The Great Divide in Personality&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;the-great-divide-of-personality&#34;&gt;two great personality trait&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; from each other.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Janice Dorn, who has a PhD in neuroscience specializing brain anatomy, an MD in psychiatry, an active trader, and a “financial psychiatrist” who has counseled about six hundred traders, observed that her extroverted clients, on average, are highly reward-sensitive, while the introverts are more conservative that pay close attention to warning signals. “My introvert traders are much more able to say ‘OK, Janice, I do feel these excited emotions coming up in me, but I understand that I can’t act on them.’ The introverts are much better at making plan, staying with a plan, being very disciplined” said Dr. Dorn, wrote Susan Cain.&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Limbic System&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;limbic-system&#34;&gt;limbic system&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, which Dr. Dorn calls the “old brain” that we share with the most primitive animals, is emotional and instinctive. It comprises various structures such as our &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Amygdala&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;amygdala&#34;&gt;amygdala&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, and it’s highly interconnected with the nucleus accumbens, brain’s “pleasure center.” According to Dr. Dorn, it constantly tells us “Yes, yes, yes! Eat more, drink more, have more sex, take lots of risk go for all the gusto you can get, and above all do not think!”. On the other hand, the “new brain” called the &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Neocortex&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;neocortex&#34;&gt;neocortex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, a part of our cerebral cortex, that is responsible for thinking, planning, language, and decision-making, some of the very faculties that makes us humans. It’s job, as Dr. Dorn puts, is to tell us “No, no, no! Don’t do that because it’s dangerous, makes no sense, and is not in your best interests, or those of your family, or of society.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we now know, extroverts are more sensitive to reward than introverts do. It’s what makes extroverts an extrovert. Richard Depue, a neurobiologist at Cornell University, conducted an experiment where he gave amphetamine, an addictive drug that activates the &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Dopamine&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;dopamine&#34;&gt;dopamine system&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;–the “reward chemical”, to groups of introverts and extroverts. His experiments shown that extroverts had stronger response and concluded that “introverts just don’t buzz as easily”. Although the exact relationship between extroversion, dopamine, and the brain’s reward system has not been conclusively established, “extrovert’s dopamine pathway appears to be more active than those of introverts,” wrote Cain.&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Buzz is sometimes a good thing. It encourage us to work and play hard. But sometimes, it pushes us to take risk that we shouldn’t take. It cause us to ignore warning signs we should be paying attention to. On the other hand, less sensitivity to buzz can sometimes make us too conservative but it also shows discipline for &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Delayed Gratification&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;delayed-gratification&#34;&gt;delayed gratification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, the unique &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: How Did Introverts Survive The Process of Evolution&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;how-did-introverts-survive-the-process-of-evolution&#34;&gt;advantage of introverts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; in an extroverted society.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 7: Why Did Wall Street Crash and Warren Buffet Prosper?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/reward-sensitivity"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/trade-off-theory</id><title type="text">Trade-Off Theory</title><updated>2021-10-21T05:39</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;square-small&#34; src=&#34;https://static.thenounproject.com/png/743-200.png&#34; title=&#34;image from Noun Project (cc)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trade-off theory suggests that everything good comes at a price and everything seemingly bad has unapparent benefits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As with the perpetual discussion between extroverts vs introverts, being an extrovert isn’t always as favorable being gregarious as is being an introverts isn’t always advantageous being analytical. The opposite is also true.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For instance, human extroverts have more sexual partners than their introverted peers but they are more likely to commit adultery and get divorced. Also, extroverts, statistically, are more athletic who exercise regularly, but introverts suffer less injuries. Extroverts are better at socializing and have wider network of social support, but commit more crimes in general.&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 6: “Franklin Was A Politician, But Eleanor Spoke Out Of Conscience”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/trade-off-theory"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/how-did-introverts-survive-the-process-of-evolution</id><title type="text">How Did Introverts Survive The Process of Evolution</title><updated>2021-10-20T06:40</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;wide&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2015/03/26/15/55/the-thinker-692959_1280.jpg&#34; title=&#34;image from Pixabay (cc)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Temperament&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;temperament&#34;&gt;low-reactives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;–the bold and the aggressive–always prevail, as do always the extroverts since the beginning of time, then how come do introverts managed to survive? Why were the meek, the sensitive, the risk-averted introverts not filtered out by the process of evolution in a harsh environment?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“There is no single best . . . personality, but rather a diversity of personalities maintained by natural selection,” writes David Sloan Wilson, an evolutionary biologist, as he describe “fast” and “slow” types. Fast being the quick-to-adapt, impulsive, and headstrong type who rushes toward danger, ambivalent of their surroundings. Slow, being the sensitive, careful, and analytical type who are slow to warm-up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elaine Aron, clinical research psychologist and author, believes that high-sensitivity were not particularly selected, but rather the vigilance and reflective traits that helped introverts survived were cherry picked by natural selection. Surely, if evolution permitted these traits to survive, it must be advantageous, if not superior, to other &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: The Great Divide in Personality&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;the-great-divide-of-personality&#34;&gt;personality traits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; that didn’t. In fact, as Aron speculates, sensitivity is a by-product of the survival of the fittest. It is the words of Aron that make these clearer:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;txt language-txt&#34;&gt;    The type that is &amp;quot;sensitive&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;reactive&amp;quot; would reflect a strategy of
    observing carefully before acting, thus avoiding dangers, failures and
    wasted energy, which would require a nervous system specially designed to
    observe and detect subtle differences. It is a strategy of &amp;quot;betting on
    a sure thing&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;looking before you leap.&amp;quot; In contrast, the active strategy
    of the [other type] is to be first, without, complete information and with
    the attendant risks--the strategy of &amp;quot;taking a long shot&amp;quot; because the &amp;quot;early
    bird catches the work&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;opportunity only knocks once.&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Susan Cain wrote, “There’s a great deal of evidence for Aron’s point of view. Evolutionary biologists once believed that every animal species evolved to fit an ecological niche, that there was one ideal set of behaviors for that niche, and that species members whose behavior deviated from that ideal would eventually die off. But it turns out that it’s not only humans that divide into those who ‘watch and wait’ and others who ‘just do it.’ More than a hundred species in the animal kingdom are organized in roughly this way.”&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As tempting as it is for us to claim that one personality trait is superior to the other, as we all know, everything comes at a price, and the &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Trade-Off Theory&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;trade-off-theory&#34;&gt;trade-off theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; best explain that there are always limitations and drawbacks to anything that lives, had live, and will live in the world as we know it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 6: “Franklin Was A Politician, But Eleanor Spoke Out Of Conscience”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/how-did-introverts-survive-the-process-of-evolution"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/why-extroverts-are-cool-and-why-introverts-are-not</id><title type="text">Why Extroverts Are Cool and Why Introverts Are Not?</title><updated>2021-10-19T05:44</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;wide&#34; src=&#34;https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2020/04/26/11/17/keep-cool-5094748_1280.jpg&#34; title=&#34;image from Pixabay (cc)&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our definition of a being “cool” have been used to describe a person being calm under pressure or someone who finesse an activity with seemingly effortless energy and nonchalant attitude. And someone who is the opposite of cool might seem anxious, weird, or easily overwhelmed, making them less desirable than their cool peers. The list goes on for the usage of the term “cool” but what exactly does being cool actually mean?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, scientifically, being “cool” has some dermatological truth to it. Among other &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: The Great Divide in Personality&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;the-great-divide-of-personality&#34;&gt;personality trait&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; tests, researchers used skin conductance to determine the physiological reaction of our body to various stimuli. Researchers recorded how much people sweat in response to noise, strong emotions, etc., and concluded that &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Temperament&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;temperament&#34;&gt;high-reactive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; introverts sweat more as compared to their &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Temperament&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;temperament&#34;&gt;low-reactive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; extrovert peers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“[Extroverts’ skin] is literally ‘thicker,’ more impervious to stimuli, cooler to touch. In fact, according to some of the scientists I spoke to, this is where our notion of being socially ‘cool’ comes from; the lower-reactive you are, the cooler your skin, the cooler you are,” wrote Susan Cain&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In common social gatherings, alcoholic drinks are almost always present, even required, to keep the edge off to help with social anxiety by lowering our levels of arousal, “cooling” the attendees down. Similarly, wearing dark sunglasses, even when its not sunny, hides the dilation of our eyes and covers part of our facial expressions which has the effect on people that magically makes the wearer cooler. Another, the slang term wearing “ice”, which refers to expensive jewelries worn as an accessory such as chain necklace or ring, is not a coincidence that the term is related to coolness. As Cain puts it, “Maybe we’ve adopted dark glasses, relaxed body language, and alcohol as signifiers precisely because they camouflage signs of a nervous system on overdrive.” Early U.S. Astronauts consider having a low heart rate, which is related to low reactivity, as a status symbol. Lieutenant Colonel John Glenn, the first American to orbit the Earth and was a presidential candidate in 1984, was known by his comrades as having a super cool pulse rate during liftoff of only 110 beats per minute–just above the normal heart rate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, polygraphs, more commonly known as lie detector test, are partially skin conductance tests. They operate on the belief that lying causes people to feel anxious which triggers their skin to sweat uncontrollably. “Incidentally, sociopaths lie at the extreme end of this coolness barometer”, stated Cain, “with extremely low levels of arousal, skin conductance, and anxiety. There is some evidence that sociopaths have damaged amygdalae.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the bright side, the lack of coolness comes with a benefit. For instance, &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: The Science of Blushing&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;the-science-of-blushing&#34;&gt;blushing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; after an embarrassing incident makes people look sincere, trustworthy and is more likely to be forgiven when they have done wrong. Conversely, having a nonchalant attitude might seem offensive to others or insensitive for lack of showing emotions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 6: “Franklin Was A Politician, But Eleanor Spoke Out Of Conscience”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/why-extroverts-are-cool-and-why-introverts-are-not"/></entry><entry><id>https://marklucernas.dev/optimal-levels-of-stimulation</id><title type="text">Optimal Levels of Stimulation</title><updated>2021-10-15T07:18</updated><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hans Eysenck, an influential research psychologist in the late 1960s, hypothesized that we humans always seek “just right” levels of stimulation&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;–input from the outside world that our brain processes. Eysenck saw the connection between &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: The Great Divide in Personality&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;the-great-divide-of-personality&#34;&gt;the two great personality trait&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and levels of stimulation: introverts find it optimally stimulating when they work alone in a quiet place, while the party-seeking extroverts chase more stimulations and can be seen more often socializing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eysenck believes that the difference between two personality traits can be found in our &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Ascending Reticular Activating System (ARAS)&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;ascending-reticular-activating-system&#34;&gt;Ascending Reticular Activating System (ARAS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, part of our brainstem that has ascending pathways to the &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container cf&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Cerebral Cortex&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;cerebral-cortex&#34;&gt;cortex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and connections to other parts of the brain which contribute to our wakefulness and behavioral arousal. Eysenck speculated that ARAS maintains the balance between over- and under-arousal by controlling the amount of stimulation that goes into our brain: introverts have wide open channels where excessive stimulations can flow, causing them to feel overwhelmed, while extroverts have narrower channels making them prone to under-arousal. “Over-arousal doesn’t produce anxiety so much as the sense that you can’t think straight–that you’ve had enough and would like to go home now. Under-arousal is something like cabin fever. Not enough is happening: you feel itchy, restless, and sluggish, like you need to get out of the house already,” wrote Susan Cain&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn1&#34; id=&#34;fnref1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understanding the underlying difference between introversion and extroversion, we can arrive to a solution, in parlance of personality psychologists, the “optimal levels of arousal”, or as Cain puts it, the “sweet spots.” An introvert in a party with profuse amount of socializing may feel overwhelmed and seek solace in a less stimulating environment, or a sweet spot. Conversely, an introvert reading within the confines of the study room found him/herself to be reading at a lower rate of speed and have been reading few sentences multiple times may feel like getting out and hanging out with friends. Again, the sweet spot or just the right amount of stimulation. The opposite can also be true for extroverts who gets bored easily and find the company of others to be their the right amount of stimulation, while being alone to be under-stimulating.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Knowing how to get into our optimal levels of arousal can also greatly improve our lifestyle and was scientifically found to be healthy. People who are aware of their sweet spots have the understanding to decide whether to stay in their current employment or start their own business. It also encourage us that &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Is Temperament Destiny?&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;is-temperament-destiny&#34;&gt;being ourselves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; has positive benefits than pretending to be someone we are not, which can &lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link-container folgeinv&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;zettel-link&#34; title=&#34;Zettel: Behavioral Leakage&#34;&gt;&lt;span data-nosnippet=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;user-select: none; color: gray&#34; title=&#34;Folgezettel&#34;&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;behavioral-leakage&#34;&gt;leak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and be mentally exhausting. Also, evidence shows that sweet spots can have life-or-death consequences. Recent study at Walter Reed Army Institute of Research suggests that introverts function better then extroverts when sleep deprived, which is cortically de-arousing condition. Drowsy extroverts behind the wheel may feel less alert and careful with their surroundings. Conversely, introverts in a loud and noisy traffic may feel overwhelmed which could impair their thinking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li id=&#34;fn1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quiet: The Power of Introverts in a World That Can’t Stop Talking by Susan Cain - Chapter 5: Beyond Temperament&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1&#34;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><link href="https://marklucernas.dev/optimal-levels-of-stimulation"/></entry></feed>